[parent 1] Juliette. get the oxygen.
Okay. stay with us.
Come on. Breathe. Okay.
- [parent 2] Here.
- [parent 1] Got it.
[Juliette] Okay.
Okay. get a pulse.
Count the beats. baby.
- One one thousand. two one thousand…
- [parent 1] Okay.
…three one thousand…
[parent 1]
We just need your heart rate to steady.
- …seven one thousand…
- Pupils are reactive.
Pulse is slowing down.
[metal creaking]
[parent 1] Okay. focus. Come on.
Focus on me now. What's your name?
Come on. baby. Come on. What's your name?
[parent 2] He's okay. He's coming to.
[parent 1] Hey. what's your name?
Jacob.
[parent 1] That's right.
And who am I?
- Mom.
- [Mom] Good.
And who's this? What's your sister's name?
J-Jerk Face.
[laughs]
[chuckles]
[Mom] Hey.
[porter] Excuse me. miss?
- [porter] Juliette Nichols?
- [Juliette] Yeah.
Thank the Founders. [pants]
There's been an accident.
[indistinct chatter]
[Sims]
Sam. I hear what you're saying. I do.
[Bernard]
We're just asking for a little discretion.
[Marnes] Discretion?
[Sims] Bernard's not wrong here.
[Sims] It'll be bad enough
when word gets out she's dead.
Add murder to that and the situation
might become unmanageable.
[Bernard] People of the Silo need comfort.
[Marnes] You know.
if it's... if it's comfort that you want.
you can get me a focused Judicial list of
every criminal who's ever crossed my path
25 levels either side
of the Mids deputy station.
Fifty levels?
And the point of that would be?
He believes she was poisoned
by someone in the Mids.
It's rat poison. I've seen it before.
You can't taste it or smell it.
Whoever did this did this last night.
when we were at the deputy station.
Somebody broke into the station?
[Marnes] We went for a walk. That's when
the murderer poisoned our bottles.
Bottles? Plural?
When was the last time you walked
the Silo with somebody. Bernie?
Oh. that's right.
you don't ever walk the Silo. do you?
What you do is. you drink
from the bottles on each other's backs
'cause it's easier
than trying to reach your own.
And if Ruth's bottle hadn't had that leak.
I-I-I'd be lying on that floor too.
- You're saying she wasn't the targ...
- [wood shattering]
Don't say "she"!
You don't say "she" about her!
That's Mayor Ruth Jahns!
She carried every level
every election for the past 40 years!
There wasn't a soul
from top to bottom didn't love her.
Everybody she met... [breathes heavily]
Because I saw... [stammers]
She was v... [exhales sharply] You know.
[sighs] Fuck. [sighs. sniffs]
You'll have the list before daybreak.
We just ask. whatever you do.
you do it quietly.
[Bernard] Miss Nichols.
What the fuck are you doing here?
I had a porter retrieve Miss Nichols.
as she's soon to be our sheriff.
[Sims] She's not.
Well. she ain't gonna be sheriff
till she's been sworn in.
[Bernard] I'm well aware of that. Deputy.
But considering
the urgency of the situation.
I thought it best that she join us.
Like you would know
what the fuck to do here anyway.
Miss Nichols.
I'm Bernard Holland. the head of IT.
Oh. I know who you are.
In accordance with the Pact.
I am now to be Mayor Pro Tem.
At least until elections can be held.
As soon as I'm sworn in.
I'll come up
to swear you into your new role as well.
If you wouldn't mind heading over
to the sheriff's department.
we need to get you up
to speed as soon as possible.
[people chattering]
[sighs]
[parent] You're gonna have to eat in
the cafeteria or at school today. honey.
I gotta be down in the clinic early again.
- Are you gonna fix her chair?
- [sighs]
I don't think it's fixable. honey.
[breathes deeply]
I'm gonna need you to do me a favor.
Mom's stuff and Jacob's stuff
are long overdue in Recycling.
If we hang on to it any longer.
they'll come in and…
- [sighs] …oh. we don't want that. right?
- No.
After school. you pick up some crates
and pack up their things.
Everything?
Jules. we can't keep things that
could be used by someone else. all right?
Come on. get your bag.
I'll walk you halfway.
[sighs]
[Sandy] Are you Nichols?
Yeah.
Keys are yours.
One opens the main door.
the other this office.
[breathes shakily]
The third. Holston's apartment.
If you know your measurements
and shoe size.
write 'em down. and I'll get you
at least one uniform by tomorrow.
You bleed or sweat through that one.
you'll be wearing it all week.
so try not to get it filthy.
Yeah.
That's Holston's.
Oh. you can give it to me.
You'll get yours after you're sworn in.
No. I'll keep it.
Is there any food?
The cafeteria will open at 5:00.
Anything now?
We just. uh.
grab-and-go three levels down.
I was told to stock
the fridge in the apartment.
but I have no idea
what you people eat down deep.
Children mostly. Sometimes each other.
[inhales deeply] Um. what's in this?
- Firearms. Restricted items.
- Files?
Some.
And the combination?
After you're sworn in.
Right. listen.
I don't know if your issue is with me
or just with anybody
from the bottom 50. but I'm finding this...
- [Sandy] What are the files you want?
- Huh?
- You were asking about files.
- Just one.
Uh. George Wilkins. Mechanical.
Look.
I get a note from the mayor that says.
"Clean out Holston's office.
Nichols is coming."
I don't know who you are.
or why you're here...
- You haven't asked.
- I don't give a damn!
The only way I've survived this week is by
following instructions. and I don't need...
I'm Holston's replacement.
which I'm guessing makes me your boss?
Yeah. I'm from the Down Deep.
I eat the same shit you eat.
Maybe with a little bit more salt.
Are we done with that?
Great.
Now. can you please get me Wilkins's file?
Can you get the door on your way out?
[Sandy scoffs]
Holston always kept it open.
[sighs]
- [mechanical clanking]
- Hmm.
- [manager] You doing this all by yourself?
- [Juliette] Yeah.
Hey. Let me see.
You're throwing
too many things down the chute.
Mechanical's complaining again. saying
90% of what you throw away. they fix.
Which is. no doubt. a load of shit.
but I gotta check.
Get it out. Run it again.
So. young lady. is this all your stuff?
My mom's. She doesn't need it anymore.
[manager] Is that so?
[Juliette] The other stuff's my brother's.
[manager] How old is he?
He was 11.
You can keep some of that stuff
if you want.
These guys.
they're not gonna know what to do with it.
What about your father? He around?
He's working.
You know. you shouldn't be
doing this alone. Not at your age.
[door unlocks]
Hi. baby.
[smoke detector blaring]
Juliette.
Goddamn! What the hell are you doing?
- I was hungry. and you weren't home.
- So you start a fire?
I was fixing the chair.
That chair can't be fixed.
- [beeping stops]
- It can. and I did.
I also took all of Mom
and Jacob's things down alone!
[sighs] Oh. honey. I'm sorry.
[inhales shakily]
This is the way things are now.
Because of you! [inhales shakily]
- No. Jules.
- I shouldn't have to do this!
[parent] Neither should I.
[sighs] What choice do we have?
- [Juliette sniffles]
- [knocks]
[parent] Jules?
Honey?
Honey!
[Juliette sobbing]
[parent] They're gone. and I can't fix it.
Not everything can be fixed.
- [crying]
- Jules?
[knocks]
[mechanical clanking continues]
- Hello.
- Hi.
May I?
[Juliette] Yeah. of course.
I'm sorry. You can sleep with that noise?
Yeah. I can't sleep without it.
Well. if you wanna get it fixed.
I suggest reaching out to maintenance.
They're a particularly territorial bunch
but good at what they do.
I can handle it.
Well. it's your choice.
You'd be making an enemy.
but I'll let you work all of that through.
I am here to swear you in as sheriff.
- With a witness and your uniform.
- [Juliette] Thanks.
[Juliette chuckles]
What's funny?
Just that you'd be the one swearing me in
when you were the one who accused me
of stealing heat tape. just…
Miss Nichols.
did you steal that tape?
No. I appropriated it 'cause we needed it.
[inhales sharply]
You were not my choice for this position.
But… [sighs] …considering recent events.
I think it best we let bygones
be bygones. no?
Of course.
Please place your hand on the Pact
and repeat after me.
[lock clicks]
I need your signature.
On what?
How's it fit?
Yeah. it's all right. Thanks.
These are the arrangements
for Jahns's funeral.
I'll handle it. You just sign. Here.
Should I read through it or…
You ever made arrangements
for a ceremonial burial?
- No.
- Then that's your answer.
[huffs] Is Marnes in?
[Sandy] Nope.
Judicial says
they don't have a Wilkins file.
Holston did leave a file for you. though.
Uh. well. not for you.
but whoever got the job.
It's right there on top.
- [radio static]
- [deputy. on radio] Mids to Central.
- [deputy] Mids to Central.
- [radio static]
Mids to Cen...
- [door opens]
- Do you not hear the radio?
- Yeah. I figured you could handle that.
- Look. it's Marnes.
[grunts] You tell me.
[grunting. breathing heavily]
Where'd you get the poison. Franky?
- I don't know. What the fuck? [groans]
- Marnes. Hey. hey. hey. hey.
- Let me talk to you.
- No!
Where'd you get the poison. Franky?
I don't know
what the fuck you're talking about.
Hey! You've got everyone freaked out.
There are kids watching.
- What the fuck are they doing here?
- [Juliette] Hey.
- You should be in school!
- It's lunch.
- Okay? Yeah?
- [panting] Yeah. okay.
[Juliette sighs]
[slurps]
Think there's another way for you to
try and find out what happened to Jahns?
You know. I've worn a badge for over
30 years. You've been sheriff half a day.
There's not a thing you can tell me
about how to do this job.
You know I didn't ask
for the badge. right?
Why'd you change your mind?
I didn't know Holston
as well as you did. but...
That's the understatement of the century.
I figured if he wanted me to have it.
I should take it.
That's bullshit.
What'd you do to him down there?
What did you say?
- What'd I do to him?
- Yeah. what did you say to him?
[Juliette sighs]
The guy you beat up. Franky.
wh... what's his story?
A year ago. Franky poisoned two levels
with bad booze.
- Bad booze isn't rat poison.
- It's poison.
Am I the only one in the Silo who gives
a fuck about finding out the truth?
No. you're not.
- You wanna know what I said to Holston?
- Yeah. I do.
I said he should've listened to his wife
'cause if he had.
maybe she'd be alive right now.
You did what?
I told him someone had been murdered.
I proved it to him.
Knowing that was a possibility.
he said he'd still have to tell Judicial
it was an accident.
He was gonna send a sign
if he found anything. so I waited.
Next time I see Sheriff Holston
is with the rest of the Silo.
when he goes out to clean.
Then the mayor gives me this.
[Marnes] "Truth."
You think that's the sign?
I don't know.
And that's why you
want George Wilkins's file.
Uh. Sandy told me.
Boy. she really doesn't like you.
[scoffs] Yeah. she's not subtle about it.
What do you want from me?
I want you to help me
to find out who killed George.
Why should I do that?
I'll help you figure out
what happened to the mayor.
You have to s-stand that far back?
If I hadn't moved my head last time.
I'd be wearing an eye patch.
[resident]
The fuck are you doing here. Marnes?
- Hello. Patrick. The sheriff and I...
- Wait. wait. who's this?
Oh. that's right. The new sheriff.
'Cause your old pal's outside.
cuddled with his lady.
Hey. Patrick Kennedy.
We are here to talk to your wife.
- [Patrick scoffs. chuckles]
- Right?
- Is that funny to you?
- Yeah.
- Go ahead. knock. Should be interesting.
- Why is that?
Couple of reasons. Marnes.
One of which being
that she's been dead for a year.
Surprised you didn't come to the funeral.
seeing as you framing her
is the reason why she's in the soil.
Yeah. uh. um. Patrick.
We all knew she was headed
for the farm the minute she met you.
Hey.
- Son of a...
- [grunts]
O-Ouch!
[exhales deeply]
I'm gonna have to follow up
on this Patrick Kennedy. am I?
'Cause he broke your nose?
No. because of robbery and extortion.
and a past jam with Judicial over relics.
[Marnes breathes deeply]
You ever see a hard drive
in Holston's safe or his apartment?
Check Recycling.
Any hard drive
or personal effects of Holston's
would've gone there
after he went out to clean.
Right.
You looking
for some kind of sign of Holston's
on this drive that'll lead you
to the truth about George Wilkins?
And what if you don't find it?
[inhales sharply] I gotta try.
[breathes deeply] Hmm.
Truth and trying mattered
to… [sniffles] …Allison too.
and it mattered to Holston.
And… [stammers. smacks lips]
…you might wanna think about that.
Hey. with Jahns.
how do you know you were the target?
Forty years as mayor. and what?
She didn't piss off one person?
Not as many as me.
Just... Listen. down in Mechanical.
someone's always got a theory
about why a machine breaks.
I deal with facts.
Jahns. she was poisoned which means...
Jahns was not a machine.
[breathes shakily] She was a person…
like no other person.
[faucet runs]
[Juliette] How about that deal?
You help me. I'll help you.
And then I can head back to Mechanical.
You can get someone else to do this job.
while you… [inhales deeply]
…live the rest of your life in peace.
Wanna think about it?
In the meantime. um.
try not kicking down any more doors.
[Marnes] Yeah. All right.
Um… [inhales deeply]
…should we get a deputy outside?
You pissed off a lot
of people today. Marnes.
I got a shotgun.
You know. there are some things
a shotgun isn't the best solution for.
I'll be fine.
[door opens]
[people chattering]
[resident] Good morning.
[sighs]
[Martha] "Dear Miss Walker.
I'm writing to you to introduce you
to my daughter. Juliette Nichols."
[Martha] Juliette Nichols?
Yes. ma'am.
Hell kind of name is Juliette?
It's from a play.
"I would like her to shadow in Mechanical.
Signed. Doctor Peter Nichols."
- That's my father.
- Yeah. I figured.
You didn't want to shadow him?
Sight of blood makes me queasy.
Plenty of blood down here.
You related to Hanna Nichols?
Yeah. She was my mother.
We don't get many visits
from where you're from.
Certainly not from kids
with notes from doctor daddies.
- What good are you to us?
- I can fix things.
- My mom taught me to fix things.
- This ain't a toy shop. kid.
If that's all you got.
I... I think I gotta send you back.
- I'm not going back.
- [Martha] Oh.
Well. listen to me. little fixer.
This isn't the place for you.
Down here. mistakes cost lives.
While you learn on the job.
you put lives in danger.
So. how'd they learn?
- Family. They were born into it.
- So was I.
You are your mother's daughter all right.
Hey. Knox?
Knox?
Tell Shirley to take this
Juliette character to the scavenge team.
- They've got five minutes.
- This is crazy.
The 12 Recycling stations are all
on different schedules.
dumping once.
at an exact time. every hour.
But it times out so that every
five minutes something else falls.
They're supposed to only dump
stuff they can't reuse or fix.
But they get lazy.
so we find things we can repair
and send back up
or use down here ourselves.
Who'd want that job?
No one. They're criminals.
What did they do?
They killed. like. a dozen people.
[chuckles] They stole something
or beat somebody.
I have no idea. But stuff falls.
They drag it.
We sort it and fix what we can
in the next room.
The stuff that we don't use goes
to the incinerator.
Primo parts go to Walker. She has a list.
Find something on it.
you take it to her directly.
She never leaves her shop. Ever.
[resident] It's about time
someone from the Down Deep rose up.
[exhales sharply]
Gives all us bottom-siders hope
things might get better around here.
[sniffs] What can I do for ya?
Um. I'm looking for something
that might've come in
from the cleanout
of Sheriff Holston's apartment.
I was on that cleanout.
A lot of tears that day.
[inhales sharply]
What in particular are you looking for?
A metal box about this big.
Could be a hard drive.
I'm also looking for about ten sheets
of paper. typescript with handwriting.
That much paper. I'd remember.
But. mmm.
I don't recall seeing anything like that.
- I'll ask the others.
- No.
Just message me directly
if anything turns up.
- I'll cover the charge.
- You got it.
Okay.
You wanted to see me?
Hey. Jules.
[Martha] Come in. Shut the door.
When you forge a letter.
you should check the spelling.
Mechanical has an H in it.
Morning after you arrived.
I sent a porter to tell your dad
you were down here.
so he wouldn't spend
the rest of his life wondering
if you'd fallen down the trash chute.
I'm not going back up.
Well.
you don't get to decide those things.
Not at 13.
Are you happy here?
I start work hours
before the lights cycle to day.
I eat lunch standing up.
And if I'm lucky.
I get a half-an-hour break.
Every night. I am exhausted.
I fall asleep before my head hits the cot.
Are you happy. Juliette?
I'm happy I really don't have time
to think about Mom or Jacob.
Or me?
Yeah. you shouldn't have to.
Mechanical doesn't need anyone
looking for an escape.
Mechanical needs workers.
people committed to ensuring
the lives of others.
Everyone in the Silo relies on us.
So. if you can't commit to that.
I don't care where you go
'cause you're not needed here.
- But I am.
- You are what?
Needed here. I'm good at this.
[clicks tongue] All right.
From now on. you shadow Knox.
Yes. ma'am.
[people chattering]
[groans]
[panting. grunting]
[knocking]
Who is it?
[Sims] It's Rob.
[Marnes panting] Hang on.
Wow. Love the new look. buddy.
Fuck you very much.
Your new boss give you that?
I got it from a guy named Patrick Kennedy.
Remember him?
Sold unsanctioned relics.
[Marnes]
He also committed a string of felonies.
Why'd he hit you?
Besides the fact
that you generally kinda invite it.
[Marnes]
Uh. I went to visit his wife. Doris.
[pants] She'd threatened me a few times
and meant it.
But. uh. fortunately for the Silo.
dear darling Doris is dead.
A fact that didn't end up
in that list that you gave me. [pants]
[Sims] You know what they say. Sam?
You wanna lose something forever.
give it to Data Management.
I forget how much people don't like you.
Who's watching your back?
- Are you volunteering?
- [chuckles]
I have good news.
Judge Meadows is ready
to make the new sheriff a former one.
Paperwork's done.
You sign along with Mayor Pencilneck.
and by morning.
Billings will be Up Top and ready
to take over the job.
Yeah. well… [panting]
…I figure we'd better hold off
on that a bit.
- Why is that?
- [Marnes groans]
Nichols was Holston's choice.
I figure she's got a right
to fail on her own.
She knows she's not wanted.
She's not gonna last long.
Send her back down mad.
She's just gonna get
Mechanical all riled up and…
It's your call. but Meadows
wants Nichols out and Billings in.
And you know when something
sticks in her craw. well...
Well. I don't work for Meadows.
But we all work for the good of the Silo.
You're right. For the good of the Silo.
Technically. I... I still have one minute
left before the cafeteria closes.
Okay.
Uh. Sheriff. uh… [chuckles]
Sorry. Sheriff.
Lukas.
- Juliette.
- Oh. Juliette?
[chuckles] Like... Like the play.
- Yeah. You... You heard of it?
- [Lukas] Yeah. of course.
Well. they don't really perform that one
anymore though. do they? [chuckles]
Oh. I... I... I don't know.
Some people say it was written by.
well. a rebel. [chuckles]
Did I just say something
that you could arrest me for?
Oh. I wouldn't know.
Okay. Well.
maybe I should just go back and get my...
Yeah. I think your minute's up. so…
Okay. [chuckles]
- Um. good night.
- Night.
[Marnes] You'd consider retiring?
Why not?
Maybe open a shop
right next to some guy who does drawings.
[Jahns] You know. I didn't come
all this way just to meet Nichols.
I wanted to spend time with you.
[cries]
And their great victory
should be celebrated with horns.
- [crowd cheering]
- [crowd blowing horns]
[sobs]
[radio static]
[Juliette. over radio] Walk?
Walker. you there?
[radio static]
- [Martha] That you. Fixer?
- Yeah.
Hey. Uh. I'm here.
[radio static]
[Martha] How goes the work?
Well. I... I might not be pulling alone.
[Martha] So. progress?
Yeah. maybe.
[Martha] Did you find an ally?
[Juliette] Perhaps.
I'll know more tomorrow.
[Martha] There's been
some progress here too.
Uh. in fact. something
that may require your insight.
Okay. give me a bit.
and I-I'll see what I can do.
[Martha] Okay. Thanks.
Uh. night.
[Juliette] Okay. Good night.
[whistling]
[beeps]
[door unlocks]
[sighing]
[exhales sharply]
[machinery whirring]
[metal clanking]
[Marnes whistling]
[keys clatter]
[both grunting. groaning]
[groaning. breathing heavily]
[groaning]
[groaning. grunting continue]
- [Marnes breathes heavily] Oh. fuck.
- [gun cocks]
[Marnes gasps. breathes heavily]
[grunts]
[grunting. panting]
[metallic clanking]
[Juliette grunts. breathing deeply]